<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Exchange Rates Status - Incident History</title>
    <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org</link>
    <description>Statuspage</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 22:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>API timeouts reported on Friday morning</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jun &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 6&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;11:00&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - This incident has been resolved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jun &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 4&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;11:39&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigating&lt;/strong&gt; - We are investigating a brief period of connection timeouts and partial unavailability on the API taking place on Friday at approximately 07:45 UTC. We will update our status page as soon as we have any further information.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 11:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/50l48sk6xbsr</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/50l48sk6xbsr</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Currencies missing in API response</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Apr &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;30&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;00:00&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - This incident has been resolved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 6&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;00:13&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; - While the technical incident that occurred yesterday has been resolved and our systems are stable, we are continuing to look into issues today regarding several currency symbols that are no longer available in our API, following the earlier incident.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The following cryptocurrency symbols, which were previously only available when specifying the &quot;show_alternative&quot; rates endpoint parameter, are affected: EAC, EMC, FCT, FTC, NMC, NVC, PPC, VTC, and XPM.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In addition, the deprecated Venezuelan Bolívar Fuerte (VEF) symbol is no longer available. The VEF currency symbol was deprecated and replaced by the newer Bolívar Soberano (VES) rate in August 2018, and this rate should be used instead. Please refer to the relevant historical Status Page update for more information about this change: https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/wrmzgmh6zwhy&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please contact us at support@openexchangerates.org if you experience any further issues connecting to our services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 5&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;09:48&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identified&lt;/strong&gt; - The issue was identified and a fix was made last night. We are continuing to monitor the results and working to prevent any re-occurence and identify downstream issues that were caused. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please note that as a result of this incident, the Cuban Convertible Peso (CUC) symbol has been temporarily removed from our latest API results. All other rates should now be available as usual.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Clients that found their integrations made a much larger volume of requests than normal (due to failed connections) should contact us at support@openexchangerates.org, regarding having their usage allowance reset.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please contact us if you experience any further issues connecting to our service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 4&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;20:42&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigating&lt;/strong&gt; - We are investigating an issue in our API that has caused certain rates to be unavailable in our service this evening. We will update this notification as soon as we have any further information.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/4ztv8qh3ztmt</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/4ztv8qh3ztmt</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delayed updates to BTC, ETH, LTC and other cryptocurrencies</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 6&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;13:40&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - This incident has been resolved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 5&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;23:41&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring&lt;/strong&gt; - Rates for BTC, ETH and LTC are updating as usual as of approximately 22:24 UTC this evening. This incident was caused by a service outage at a third-party provider, and was not related to other technical issues over the past 48 hours. We are continuing to monitor these rates, as well as identifying changes that will prevent this issue from re-occurring, and we will provide a further update to our Status Page should any more information become available about this.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please note that while this particular incident is resolved, a number of cryptocurrency rates that were previously available in our application (under the &apos;alternative&apos; rates endpoint parameter) are currently unavailable. Please refer to the following Status Page notification, where we will post updates regarding these: https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/4ztv8qh3ztmt&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please contact us at support@openexchangerates.org if you experience any further issues relating to BTC, ETH or LTC rates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 5&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;17:10&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigating&lt;/strong&gt; - We are currently experiencing delays updating BTC, ETH, LTC, and other cryptocurrency rates (available via our &apos;alternative&apos; endpoint parameter), which is unrelated to the service issues taking place yesterday and earlier today. We will provide updates via this notification as soon as we have more information. In the meantime, customers requiring updates for these symbols may wish to temporarily switch to an alternative service (such as the Coinbase API) to receive data for these symbols.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 13:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/w1vfxfz8q0s8</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/w1vfxfz8q0s8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slow responses from Open Exchange Rates API</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 5&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;00:52&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - This incident has been resolved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 4&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;19:21&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigating&lt;/strong&gt; - We are again experiencing slow responses from our API. We will update this notification as soon as we have further information.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/d1hgcfcfgw2f</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/d1hgcfcfgw2f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slow response times on API</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 4&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;17:36&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - This incident has been resolved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 4&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;16:49&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigating&lt;/strong&gt; - We are currently investigating slow response times affecting some API clients. Please bear with us for more updates.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 17:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/8hc15ncdz1yc</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/8hc15ncdz1yc</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Factoring issue with USD/UGX (Ugandan Shilling) rate on 11 September 2020</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Sep &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;14&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;09:35&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - This incident has been resolved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Sep &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;11&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;09:00&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigating&lt;/strong&gt; - We are currently experiencing an issue with USD/UGX (Ugandan Shilling) currency rates, which is also affecting other currency pairs with UGX. The USD/UGX rate is currently reporting at approximately 37.06, instead of the correct value of approximately 3,706. We are working with our data contributors to identify and resolve this issue as soon as possible. Other currency rates that do not involve the UGX symbol are not affected.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 09:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/6mf9px4jlpdh</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/6mf9px4jlpdh</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Root CA certificate expiry</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jun &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 2&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;08:53&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - This incident has been resolved. Please contact us at support@openexchangerates.org if you require any further assistance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;May &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;31&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;10:50&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring&lt;/strong&gt; - This issue has now been resolved, however some clients may need to make modifications to their integration in order to continue to connect to our API, as our SSL certificate has been updated (for the majority of clients affected by this incident however no change should be required). We are continuing to monitor the situation and will update this notice if anything changes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please contact us at support@openexchangerates.org if you experience any further issues connecting to our API, or if you need any additional support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;May &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;30&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;21:28&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identified&lt;/strong&gt; - We are continuing to investigate the issue concerning the Root CA expiry.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please contact us at support@openexchangerates.org if you are affected by this issue, or if you need any advice concerning the temporary workaround.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;May &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;30&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;19:03&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigating&lt;/strong&gt; - We are currently investigating an issue affecting a number of clients, which appears to be the result of the expiry of the AddTrust External CA Root (root certificate) on 30 May 2020. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;While our SSL certificate is valid until 5 January 2021, and our API instances and website are fully operational at present, clients that are affected by this issue may receive &quot;Certificate expired&quot; errors on attempting to connect to our API.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We are currently working to identify which clients may be affected by this issue, and the steps that are required to remedy it. We will update this notice as soon as we have any further information.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please contact support@openexchangerates.org if you experience any issues connecting to our service.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 08:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/my4vwrll12mm</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/my4vwrll12mm</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Routine maintenance causing service outage</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jul &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;20&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;21:21&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - No further incident has been observed related to today&apos;s database maintenance. In total, we observed a total of around 3 minutes of unplanned service downtime, comprised of several shorter outages occurring between  15:31 UTC to 15:35 UTC on Saturday afternoon. We do not anticipate any further issues in relation to this maintenance and we apologise for any inconvenience this may have caused. Please don&apos;t hesitate to contact us at support@openexchangerates.org if you have any questions or concerns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jul &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;20&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;15:40&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring&lt;/strong&gt; - We are monitoring a minor service outage occurring on the openexchangerates.org API and website on Saturday afternoon. This began at approximately 15:30 UTC and was caused by scheduled database maintenance. Requests may receive &quot;Service Unavailable&quot; errors while this is occurring. We apologise for any inconvenience this may cause.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 21:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/f9cgshg0gx0n</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/f9cgshg0gx0n</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renewal of SSL certificate</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 7&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;14:00&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Completed&lt;/strong&gt; - The scheduled maintenance has been completed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 6&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;14:01&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In progress&lt;/strong&gt; - Scheduled maintenance is currently in progress. We will provide updates as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 6&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;13:45&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheduled&lt;/strong&gt; - We will shortly be renewing the SSL certificate covering https://openexchangerates.org and its subdomains. This should not have any effect on your API integration, however please feel free to contact us at support@openexchangerates.org if you need any support, or have any questions or concerns about this update.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 14:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/28vpsbjyspdn</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/28vpsbjyspdn</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increased API response times on 27th December 2018</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 3&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;15:44&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - This incident has been resolved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Dec &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;28&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;08:40&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigating&lt;/strong&gt; - We are investigating a spike in API response times that affected a number of clients&apos; integrations yesterday (December 27th) between 12:00 and 22:00 UTC. Please contact support@openexchangerates.org with any questions or concerns related to this issue.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 15:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/lcwghdfvvs52</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/lcwghdfvvs52</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Addition of bid/ask prices for currencies GEL, IDR, IRR, SBD, TOP, VND</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Dec &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;13&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;23:55&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Completed&lt;/strong&gt; - The scheduled maintenance has been completed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Dec &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;13&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;00:00&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheduled&lt;/strong&gt; - Dear clients,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Starting today (Thursday 13th December 2018), we will begin providing &apos;bid&apos; and &apos;ask&apos; prices for the following currencies, where specifically requested using the &apos;show_bid_ask&apos; API option:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;- Georgian Lari (GEL)&lt;br /&gt;- Indonesian Rupiah (IDR)&lt;br /&gt;- Iranian Rial (IRR)&lt;br /&gt;- Solomon Islands Dollar (SBD)&lt;br /&gt;- Tongan Pa&apos;anga (TOP)&lt;br /&gt;- Vietnamese Dong (VND)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Previously, when using the &apos;show_bid_ask&apos; API option to request currency prices, these currency symbols would return a &apos;mid&apos; value only (with the expected &apos;bid&apos; and &apos;ask&apos; values absent from each rate object). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With this update, the two additional values will now be added to the rate object for each affected symbol (in addition to the &apos;mid&apos; value as expected).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This change only affects API requests using the &apos;show_bid_ask&apos; option, and all values previously expected in your API responses will still be provided as before, therefore no changes are required to maintain functionality. However, if your integration was not previously set up to expect bid and ask prices for the above symbols, you may now wish to update it to take advantage of the new values.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can find further details about our Bid/Ask API option in our documentation:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;https://docs.openexchangerates.org/docs/bid-ask-prices&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please don&apos;t hesitate to contact us at support@openexchangerates.org if you have any questions or comments, or need any further support regarding this change.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kind regards,&lt;br /&gt;Open Exchange Rates Team&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/gn70wc5jhcxj</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/gn70wc5jhcxj</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issue with KRW (South Korean Won) rate multiplication</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Sep &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 2&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;11:31&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - This incident was resolved with an update on Monday 27th August with no recurrence. We are contacting affected clients. Please email us at support@openexchangerates.org if you have any questions or concerns about this update.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Aug &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;27&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;02:14&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identified&lt;/strong&gt; - We are investigating an issue affecting KRW (South Korean Won) rates available via our latest.json API endpoint on Sunday evening, during which clients may have received rates at a ratio of 1:100. We have put a temporary solution in place, and will publish more details as they become available.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 11:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/g1wvhc8nqvr7</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/g1wvhc8nqvr7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Scheduled] Redenomination of Venezuelan Bolívar (VEF) to Bolívar Soberano (VES) on 20th August 2018</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Aug &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;20&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;23:59&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Completed&lt;/strong&gt; - The scheduled maintenance has been completed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Aug &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;20&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;00:00&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In progress&lt;/strong&gt; - Scheduled maintenance is currently in progress. We will provide updates as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Aug &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;16&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;13:04&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheduled&lt;/strong&gt; - Dear clients,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The redenomination of the Venezuelan Bolívar (ISO 4217 symbol:  &quot;VEF&quot;) to the Venezuelan Bolívar Soberano (ISO 4217 symbol: &quot;VES&quot;) is scheduled to go into effect on 20th August, 2018. The conversion rate is 100,000 (old) Bolívar to 1 (new) Bolívar Soberano (100,000:1).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We will begin providing rate updates for the new Bolívar from this date, both in our Latest and Historical API endpoints, under the ISO 4217 symbol &quot;VES&quot;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There will not be any API downtime or maintenance period associated with this change.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We will continue to provide rates for the old Bolivar (VEF), according to the official exchange rate between the two, until further notice. This is intended to prevent disruption to clients that rely on the VEF value being available, however we advise affected clients to update their systems to the new rate as soon as possible.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For more information about this redenomination, please refer to the ISO 4217 amendment documents below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;– https://www.currency-iso.org/dam/downloads/dl_currency_iso_amendment_166.pdf&lt;br /&gt;– https://www.currency-iso.org/dam/downloads/dl_currency_iso_amendment_167.pdf&lt;br /&gt;– https://www.currency-iso.org/dam/downloads/dl_currency_iso_amendment_168.pdf&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Further information:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;– https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Venezuelan_bol%C3%ADvar#Bol%C3%ADvar_soberano&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you would like to speak to us about these changes, or have any questions or concerns, please contact support@openexchangerates.org and we’ll be happy to help.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kind regards,&lt;br /&gt;Open Exchange Rates Team&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 23:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/wrmzgmh6zwhy</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/wrmzgmh6zwhy</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We're adding two new currency denominations (STN and MRU) on 1st January 2018</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 1&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;09:00&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Completed&lt;/strong&gt; - The scheduled maintenance has been completed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Dec &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;19&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;14:32&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheduled&lt;/strong&gt; - Dear clients,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On 1st January 2018, we will add two new currency rates to our API endpoints, in accordance with currency re-denominations taking place in Mauritania and São Tomé and Príncipe. This change will not involve any API downtime or scheduled maintenance period.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1) The São Tomé and Príncipe Dobra (ISO 4217 symbol: “STD”) is being replaced by the new Dobra (ISO 4217 symbol: “STN”), at a conversion rate of 1000:1 (i.e. 1000 old Dobras to 1 new Dobra).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2) The Mauritanian Ouguiya (ISO 4217 symbol: “MRO”) is being replaced by the new Ouguiya (ISO 4217 symbol: “MRU”), at a conversion rate of 10:1 (i.e. 10 old Ouguiya  to 1 new Ouguiya).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In each case, the old and new currency denominations will run concurrently from 1 January 2018 to 30 June 2018. Open Exchange Rates will therefore provide both the new and old symbols side-by-side during this period.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please refer to the following pages for more information about each of these currencies:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1) https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/São_Tomé_and_Príncipe_dobra#Redenomination_of_the_dobra&lt;br /&gt;2) https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mauritanian_ouguiya#Redenomination_of_the_ouguiya&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can also download the related ISO 4217 amendments below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1) https://www.currency-iso.org/dam/downloads/dl_currency_iso_amendment_164.docx&lt;br /&gt;2) https://www.currency-iso.org/dam/downloads/dl_currency_iso_amendment_165.docx&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you would like to speak to us about these changes, or have any questions or concerns, please contact  support@openexchangerates.org and we’ll be happy to help.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kind regards,&lt;br /&gt;Open Exchange Rates Team&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/mtm1d2f4f05z</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/mtm1d2f4f05z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inverted rates for some digital currencies</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Sep &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;16&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;11:58&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - Dear clients,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In an issue related to yesterday&apos;s changes, certain alternative digital currency rates – including DASH, STR, XMR and XRP (but not including BTC, LTC and ETH) – were published as inverted prices throughout the night. This was due to a provider error, which has now been resolved, and we do not anticipate further related issues. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Going forward, we are working on broad improvements to our line-up of digital currencies, which will enable us to feature new popular digital assets and a wider range and granularity of information.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please contact us at support@openexchangerates.org with any questions or concerns.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 11:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/8cbhp5gpzp62</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/8cbhp5gpzp62</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delayed prices for some digital currency rates</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Sep &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;15&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;23:08&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - Dear clients,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have resolved an issue which caused some digital currency prices, including Dash (DASH), Monero (XMR) and Stellar (STR), to be delayed for up to 36 hours until this evening (Friday 15th September). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;While deploying changes to correct this issue, these and other prices in our &quot;alternative&quot; rates set may have become briefly unavailable and/or unstable for brief periods between 20:00 and 23:00 UTC.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Prices for Bitcoin (BTC), Ethereum (ETH) and Litecoin (LTC) were not affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We sincerely apologise for any inconvenience this may have caused. Please contact us at support@openexchangerates.org if you have any questions or concerns regarding this issue.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 23:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/8k5c7lm6n6q1</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/8k5c7lm6n6q1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delayed updates for certain currency rates today</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Aug &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;17&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;09:45&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - This incident has been resolved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Aug &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;16&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;15:44&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring&lt;/strong&gt; - We have resolved the issue, and all digital currency rates are updating as normal. We will post a final update on this incident shortly, but please contact us if you have any comments or questions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Aug &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;16&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;15:15&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identified&lt;/strong&gt; - We have installed a temporary solution addressing the primary issue, which affected all digital currencies, as well as a small number of exotic and alternative currency rates. Rate updates may be delayed up to 60 minutes, while we establish a permanent fix. We&apos;ll provide more update as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Aug &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;16&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;15:03&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigating&lt;/strong&gt; - We are looking into delays in rate updates for certain currency rates, including Bitcoin and other digital currencies, which began around midnight UTC. Major world currencies and the majority of exotic currencies are not affected. We will provide an update as soon as we have further information.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 09:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/lyn9mlh6p0kq</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/lyn9mlh6p0kq</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large fluctuations for several exotic currencies</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Aug &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;17&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;09:10&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - We have resolved this incident affecting five exotic currency rates. This issue began at approx. 10pm last night (16th August), when rates for IRR, STD, VND, IDR and KGS appeared to fluctuate widely, and was resolved at 8:35am today (17th August). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The following currencies were affected:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;IDR - Indonesian Rupiah&lt;br /&gt;IRR - Iranian Rial&lt;br /&gt;KGS - Kyrgystani Som&lt;br /&gt;STD - São Tomé and Príncipe Dobra&lt;br /&gt;VND - Vietnamese Dong&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rapid rate fluctuations were based on information received from contributors and passing safety checks, and we&apos;re continuing to look into how this happened to prevent it from happening again. We apologise for any trouble caused by this incident.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Aug &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;17&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;08:40&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigating&lt;/strong&gt; - In an issue related to the fix that we made yesterday, rates for five currencies (IRR, STD, VND, IDR, KGS) fluctuated widely in error overnight. This was due to an issue at source for these rates, which we have now corrected. We are assessing the extent of the issue and will provide further update shortly.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 09:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/3jhvg9scy50g</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/3jhvg9scy50g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upstream AWS issue caused 5XX errors and timeouts this morning</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jul &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 1&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;14:40&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - The issue that affected your API service on June 29th was caused by an unusual underlying hardware failure at Amazon Web Services, relating to our Redis ElastiCache. AWS have informed us that the failover process (by which the master node is replaced by a replica in the event of failure) encountered a rare unrecoverable error, and manual intervention was needed by their technicians to correct it. There have not been any related issues since then.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jun &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;29&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;09:45&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring&lt;/strong&gt; - We experienced an API outage this morning, caused by upstream issues at our infrastructure and cloud services provider, Amazon Web Services (AWS), in their US East (N. Virginia) region.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This incident manifested as a high number of 5XX errors and timeouts for our API clients, lasting for a period of about 2 hours between approximately 06:05 and 08:07 UTC.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Our platform is built on AWS for high availability, with multiple layers of automatic failover and redundancy. As soon as we realised failover was not happening as expected, we worked with AWS support to identify the issue and were told &quot;There was a internal hardware failure, that is supposed to be automatically recovered, but the recovery process failed.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were able to resolve the issue and service returned to normal shortly after 8am. We are continuing to monitor throughout the day and waiting on further post-mortem from AWS. Going forward we are also investigating further safeguards or precautions we can take against such issues which arise outside of our control.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;While our API did not suffer a total outage, during the failure period clients received a high proportion of failures and extremely high latency for any successful responses. We sincerely apologise for any issues caused by this outage.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you have any questions or concerns about this incident, please don&apos;t hesitate to contact us at support@openexchangerates.org.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 14:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/qj60ty85glln</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/qj60ty85glln</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We are removing two deprecated currencies (BYR and ZMK) on 10th May 2017</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;May &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;10&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;00:15&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Completed&lt;/strong&gt; - The scheduled maintenance has been completed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;May &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;10&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;00:00&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In progress&lt;/strong&gt; - Scheduled maintenance is currently in progress. We will provide updates as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Apr &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;25&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;12:38&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheduled&lt;/strong&gt; - On 10th May 2017, we will remove two officially deprecated currencies from our live rates. These are:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;– Belarusian Ruble (pre-July 2016), ISO currency code: &apos;BYR&apos;&lt;br /&gt;– Zambian Kwacha (pre-January 2013), ISO currency code: &apos;ZMK&apos;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After May 10th these two symbols will no longer be available in our &apos;latest.json&apos; and &apos;currencies.json&apos; API endpoints and will be absent from historical API responses after this date. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This change will not involve any outage or downtime.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;BYR was replaced by BYN on 1 July 2016 and both circulated in parallel until January 2017. ZMK was replaced by ZMW on 1 January 2013 (as noted in our &apos;Currencies&apos; API endpoint), and ceased to be legal tender on 30 June 2013, but remained exchangeable at commercial banks and other agents. Following consultation with our clients, each of these rates remained available in our live API for historical reference only, and are now being safely retired.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can learn more about each of these currencies (and their earlier incarnations) below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;– https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Belarusian_ruble&lt;br /&gt;– https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zambian_kwacha&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please contact us with any questions or comments about this change.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Best wishes,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Open Exchange Rates Team&lt;br /&gt;support@openexchangerates.org&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/0cvlppjvdb1q</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/0cvlppjvdb1q</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slow API responses</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Apr &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;23&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;09:01&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - We have now resolved the underlying cause and all systems are back to full health. This was a caching issue, which caused slow responses and intermittent timeouts while connecting to the API, but did not result in any major outage. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please don&apos;t hesitate to contact us at support@openexchangerates.org with any questions or concerns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Apr &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;23&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;02:18&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigating&lt;/strong&gt; - We are investigating an issue causing slow API connections and occasional timeouts for some clients. We appreciate your patience and will provide further update as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 09:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/bypkshnh6dts</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/bypkshnh6dts</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Removing four deprecated currencies – EEK, MTL, LVL and LTL – on 31 March 2017</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Mar &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;31&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;07:24&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Completed&lt;/strong&gt; - We have completed this update. Regular API service was not affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please contact us at support@openexchangerates.org if you have any questions or comments about this change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;30&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;17:06&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheduled&lt;/strong&gt; - Dear clients,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On 31 March 2017, we will remove four officially deprecated currencies from our &apos;latest.json&apos; API. These are:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;– Estonian Kroon (ISO currency code: EEK), succeeded by the Euro on 1 January 2015.&lt;br /&gt;– Maltese Lira (ISO currency code: MTL), succeeded by the Euro on 1 January 2008.&lt;br /&gt;– Lithuanian Litas (ISO currency code: LTL), succeeded by the Euro on 1 January 2015.&lt;br /&gt;– Latvian Lats (ISO currency code: LVL), succeeded by the Euro on 1 January 2014.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These currencies were convertible for a short period of time following their replacement by the Euro and were available in our live API for historical reference.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They will continue to be available in our &apos;historical&apos; API and this change will not involve any outage or downtime.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can learn more about each of these currencies below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;– https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Estonian_kroon&lt;br /&gt;– https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maltese_lira&lt;br /&gt;– https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lithuanian_litas&lt;br /&gt;– https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latvian_lats&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please don&apos;t hesitate to contact us if you have any questions, comments or concerns about this change.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Open Exchange Rates&lt;br /&gt;support@openexchangerates.org&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 07:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/26dw349l0mj9</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/26dw349l0mj9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Scheduled] Adding two new currencies, CNH and SSP, on 27 March 2017 (no API downtime)</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Mar &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;27&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;07:53&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Completed&lt;/strong&gt; - The scheduled maintenance has been completed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Mar &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;13&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;14:33&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scheduled&lt;/strong&gt; - Dear clients,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We are pleased to announce that on 27 March 2017, we will add two new currencies to our API. These are: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;– South Sudanese Pound (ISO currency code: SSP)&lt;br /&gt;– Chinese Yuan &apos;Offshore&apos; (ISO currency code: CNH)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Both will appear in our standard `rates` response. They will also be available in our `historical`, `time-series` and `convert` API endpoints beginning on the same date, and each will be available as a `base` currency.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This change will not involve any API downtime and there is no change to any of the API request or response formats.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can learn more about each of these currencies below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;– https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/South_Sudanese_pound&lt;br /&gt;– https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Renminbi#Other_markets&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please don&apos;t hesitate to contact us if you have any questions or comments about this change. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Open Exchange Rates &lt;br /&gt;support@openexchangerates.org&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 07:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/ksgqx00161p4</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/ksgqx00161p4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caching issue caused API timeouts and 500 errors for approximately 4 hours</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Mar &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;17&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;19:15&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - This issue began at around midnight UTC on the 17th March, and was resolved at approximately 4am UTC, with full service restored by 4.45am.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This was an uncharacteristic outage, triggered by a spike in requests occurring shortly after midnight UTC, combined with an unforeseen issue with AWS ElastiCache, which led to critically high database connections and CPU utilisation. At this point, clients began receiving timeouts, and began retrying their requests at a high frequency, which further multiplied the issue [1]. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;By this stage, our auto-scaling infrastructure was not able to mitigate the issue and manual intervention was required. After investigating to ascertain the root causes, we rolled out a temporary solution which resolved the immediate bottlenecks. This included temporarily switching off API usage logging, and doubling our overall database capacity (logging has since been restored and clients&apos; usage statistics are fully up-to-date).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We then worked to identify, implement and deploy a number of long-term solutions and caching improvements in response to the events that directly preceded this outage and the specific failures that they triggered, and we continued to monitor throughout the day. We are confident that the improvements we have made today will prevent this issue from happening again.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We sincerely apologise for any inconvenience this outage may have caused you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please don&apos;t hesitate to contact us at support@openexchangerates.org with any questions, comments or concerns about this incident.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kind regards,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;– Open Exchange Rates Team&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[1] Retrying failed requests is a common integration practice, although we strongly recommend waiting at least 1 second in between retries to maximise the chance of a successful response.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Mar &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;17&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;04:38&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring&lt;/strong&gt; - We have resolved the immediate issue and API service has returned to normal. We are continuing to monitor and apologise for any inconvenience caused.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Mar &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;17&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;04:21&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; - We have identified an issue in our AWS caching infrastructure which began at approximately 00:00 UTC on March 17th and caused a large volume of 500 errors and timeouts on API requests. We have performed a number of maintenance procedures to stabilise the issue and are now working to implement a solution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Mar &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt;17&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;02:33&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identified&lt;/strong&gt; - We are looking into an API platform issue, which is causing intermittent timeouts and 500 errors for API clients. We will update as soon as we have any further information.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 19:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/gzp9fgqx2f7k</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/gzp9fgqx2f7k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Resolved] Exchange rates API experiencing intermittent failures</title>
      <description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 9&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;15:40&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resolved&lt;/strong&gt; - This platform issue caused request timeouts for many of our API clients, between approximately 00:30 UTC and 13:00 UTC on January 1st. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This resulted from an unprecedented number of API requests on New Year&apos;s Day, occurring in a way that did not allow our platform to efficiently auto-scale, due to an unexpected bottleneck between our database and cache.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We began investigation as soon as we became aware of this issue, and resolved it with a deployment later in the day. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Although a small number of clients continued to experience occasional timeouts for up to 48 hours afterwards, we have not experienced a recurrence of this issue. We have since made further infrastructure updates to safeguard your service. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We sincerely apologise for any inconvenience this may have caused you. Please rest assured that we continue to closely monitor our API platform and responses for unexpected behaviour, providing you with the consistent and stable service availability you expect.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please don&apos;t hesitate to contact us if you have any questions or concerns about this incident.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Warm regards,&lt;br /&gt;Open Exchange Rates Team&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 1&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;17:29&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring&lt;/strong&gt; - This incident caused connection timeouts for a large number of API clients. We have now deployed a fix and will continue to monitor throughout the day, with a post-mortem to follow shortly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 1&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;10:18&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; - We are continuing to investigate this issue and will provide an update as soon as we have further information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Jan &lt;var data-var=&apos;date&apos;&gt; 1&lt;/var&gt;, &lt;var data-var=&apos;time&apos;&gt;07:05&lt;/var&gt; UTC&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigating&lt;/strong&gt; - A number of clients have reported receiving timeouts while connecting to our API over the past few hours. We are investigating and will respond as soon as we have further information.&lt;/p&gt;      </description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 15:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <link>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/9wkpyn50bcsz</link>
      <guid>https://status.openexchangerates.org/incidents/9wkpyn50bcsz</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
